Criag Lawyer

160 Lookout Loop, North Augusta, SC 29841

(912)320-7056

Cjl1197@gmail.com



www.linkedin.com/in/craiglawyer/

As an aspiring computer programmer, I am excited to transition into a new career field after serving in the army for 20 years. Through my military experience, I have polished my ability to approach challenges with a disciplined and detail-oriented mindset, and I am eager to apply these skills to programming. I am committed to continuous learning and growth in the field of computer science, and I believe that my dedication, work ethic, and adaptability will make me a valuable asset to any programming team.

Experience

JANUARY 2023 - PRESENT

Programming Tutor/Proctor/Aiken Technical College, Graniteville, SC

As a programming tutor at Aiken Tech, I provided one-on-one and group tutoring sessions to students in programming languages such as C++, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Visual Basic, React, and MySQL databases. I also monitored the computer lab and assisted students with technical issues, administered and proctored tests.

JUNE 2012 - AUGUST 2014

Special Agent/United States Army Criminal Investigation Command

As a Special Agent in the United States Army from October 2011 to September 2020, I conducted investigations into felony crimes, including evidence collection and processing, coordinated with other law enforcement agencies to gather evidence and witness testimony, and prepared reports and testified in court. In addition to this experience, I bring to the table 20 years of service in the Army, that taught me leadership skills that can be applied to the programming field.

Skills

C++ • JavaScript • HTML and CSS • Visual Basic • React • Databases • Problem Solving • Conflict Resolution • PHP

Education

AUGUST 2021 - PRESENT

Currentyl pursuing an Associates Degree in Applied Science with an emphasis in Programming / Aiken Technical College, Graniteville, SC

References

Available upon request